https://www.fragrancedirect.co.uk/privacy-notice.html

COOKIES ON
FRAGRANCEDIRECT.CO.UK
By selecting 'Accept' you allow Fragrance Direct to use cookies to give you the best experience on our website. We use cookies to collect you device and browser information for Functional and Marketing purposes. Without Functional Cookies you will be able to browse the site however you will not be able to place an order. We use Marketing Cookies for sharing your browsing data with carefully selected advertising partners for marketing and personalisation purposes. Please visit our Cookie Policy page for more information.
READ MORE
accept
MANAGE COOKIES
GBP
USD
EUR
DKK
SEK
Jimmy Choo
JOOP!
Featured Brands
Jean Paul Gaultier
L'Oreal Men Expert
Lab Series
Lacoste
Michael Kors
Paco Rabanne
Prada
Sofa-Ready Skincare
Miss Them? Gift Them!
Hygiene Sale
Featured Brands
Australian Bodycare
Bomb Cosmetics
DECLÉOR
Dermalogica
Elemis
Note
New Arrivals
Miss them? Gift them!
Top Gift Sets For Her
Top Gift Sets For Him
Featured Brands
Armani
Calvin Klein
Davidoff
DECLÉOR
Dermalogica
Featured Brands
JOOP!
Issey Miyake
Lacoste
Marc Jacobs
Nina Ricci
Nuxe
Ralph Lauren
Prada
Versace
Moosehead
Morris & Co.
Moschino
Mount Purious
MR Jamie Stevens
Muelhens
MUGLER
Mustang
My Trusty
N
Slika
So...?
So Eco
SOSU by SJ
SPLAT
St. Moriz
St Tropez
Stella McCartney
Stila
Stoneglow
Privacy Notice
Fragrance Direct takes your privacy very seriously. The privacy notice governs and details the main privacy principle Fragrance Direct ("we", "us", "our") applies to the data we collect and process through our services. The privacy notices describe how Fragrance Direct collects, uses, shares and secure personal information through our services, and also describes your choices regarding our use and your access to your personal information.
What information we collect/hold and why?
TYPE OF INFORMATION
PURPOSES
LEGAL BASIS OF PROCESSING
Name, address, telephone number, email address
We use the information to register and maintain customer accounts
Legitimate Interest
Name, email address, date of birth
We use the information if the individuals participate in competitions or prize draws
Legitimate Interest
Credit / Debit card details
Card details are only used to process payment for products purchased
Legitimate Interest
Customer order history
We hold this information to help customers to track previous orders and make re-ordering easy
Legitimate Interest
Customer's purchase history
We hold purchase history information to comply with HMRC requirement
Legal obligation
Email address
We use email address to send out E-Newsletter about our new products and offers
Consent
Internet protocol (IP) address, browser type, URLs of referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, information you search for (via cookies)
We collect these details to improve browsing experience, functionality, security and performance of the website
Legitimate Interest
How do we protect your personal data:
We will not transfer your personal data outside the EU without your consent.
We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect person information you provide against accidental, unlawful or unauthorised destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use.
Our checkout process uses industry standard SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) 128-bit encryption which secures your data. However, submission of information over the internet are never entirely secure.
We process your payments using secure Adyen payment gateway. Click here to find more about Adyen security.
We will notify you promptly in the event of any breach of your personal data which might expose you to serious risk.
Who else has access to the information you provide us?
We may pass your personal data to third parties who are authorised data processors or service providers (i.e. Royal mail, Adyen) to us for the purposes of completing tasks and providing services to you on our behalf. We have contracts in place with our data processors. This means that they cannot do anything with your personal information unless we have instructed them to do so. They will not share your personal information with any organisation apart from us. They will also hold the data securely and retain it for the period we instruct.
How long do we keep your information?
We will hold your personal data on our systems for as long as you are registered with us and for as long afterwards as it is in our legitimate interest to do so or for as long as necessary to comply with our legal obligations. We will review your personal data every year to establish whether we are still entitled to process it. If we decide that we are not entitled to do so, we will stop processing your personal data except that we will retain your personal data in an archived form to comply with future legal obligations (i.e. compliance with tax requirements and exemptions). We will securely destroy all personal information once we no longer need it.
E-newsletter and competitions:
We offer you the opportunity to opt-in to subscribe to our e-newsletter. However, you can easily opt-out any time either by clicking on unsubscribe link found in the bottom of the e-newsletter or updating the communication preferences. Alternatively, you can also opt-out by contacting us. Similarly, you can also opt-in or opt-out to receive e-newsletters while participating in competitions or prize draws.
Targeted advertising:
Micro-targeting, we allow selected third-parties to use tracking pixels on the site to track browsing habits and interactions across the site.
We use third-party providers Criteo, RTB House and Emarsys to serve targeted advertisements on our behalf. These parties use information they gather from on-site cookies. If you would like to opt out of this retargeting or view corresponding privacy policies click here for Criteo, click here for RTB House and click here for Emarsys
Klarna:
In order to be able to offer you Klarna’s payment options, we will pass to Klarna certain details of your personal information, such as contact and order details, in order for Klarna to assess whether you qualify for their payment options and to tailor the payment options for you. General information on Klarna you can find here. Your personal data is handled in accordance with applicable data protection law and in accordance with the information in Klarnas privacy statement.
Information we collect from you on our website:
Cookies:
We and our authorized partners use cookies and other information gathering technologies for a variety of purposes. These technologies may provide us with personal information, information about devices and networks you utilize to access our Website, and other information regarding your interactions with our Website. For detailed information about the use of cookies in our Website, click here.
Logs:
We gather certain information and store it in log files when you interact with our Website and Services. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses as well as browser type, internet service provider, URLs of referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, information you search for, locale and language preferences, identification numbers associated with your devices, your mobile carrier, and system configuration information.
Analytics:
We collect analytics information when you use the Website to help us improve them. We may also share anonymous data about your actions on our Website with third-party google analytics. Click here to view google analytics data privacy
Live chat service:
We use a third-party provider Zendesk, to supply and support our Live Chat service.
If you use the Live Chat service we may collect your name, email address or any other personal details you choose to share with us at the time. For more information click here.
Your rights :
You have rights under the GDPR :
to access your personal data
to be provided with information about how your personal data is processed
to have your personal data corrected
to have your personal data erased in certain circumstances
to object to or restrict how your personal data is processed
to have your personal data transferred to yourself or to another business in certain circumstances
to have the right to complaint about how we process your personal data
You can read more about these rights here
Complaints and Queries:
We try to meet the highest standards when collecting and using personal information. For this reason, we take any complaints we receive about this very seriously. We encourage people to bring it to our attention if they think that our collection or use of information is unfair, misleading or inappropriate. We would also welcome any suggestions for improving our procedures.
This privacy notice was drafted with brevity and clarity in mind. It does not provide exhaustive detail of all aspects of our collection and use of personal information. However, we are happy to provide any additional information or explanation needed. Contact us for making any such request.
If you want to make a complaint about the way we have processed your personal information, you can contact the Information Commissioner's Office in their capacity as the statutory body which oversees data protection law www.ico.org.uk/concerns
Links to other websites:
This privacy notice does not cover the links within our website linking to other websites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on the other websites you visit.
Changes to this privacy notice:
We keep our privacy notice under regular review. You are advised to check our website www.fragrancedirect.co.uk regularly for any amendments.
How to contact us:
If you want to request information about our privacy notice, you can email, phone or write to:
Data Protection Officer, Fragrance Direct, Garrison House, Byrons Lane, Macclesfield, Cheshire, United Kingdom SK11 7JW
Call Centre Hours:
Copyright © 2019 Fragrance Direct. All rights reserved | help@fragrancedirect.co.uk
